Snehasish Guha Roy (1) Featured

Information Technology Analyst seeking roles in Software Development, Application Programming, Business Process Analysis, Data Validation, Solution Architecture, Root Cause Analysis, Agile Methodology, Project Management, Core Java, MySQL, JavaScript, Linux



Current Designation: Information Technology Analyst Total Experience: 6 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Tata Consultancy Services Notice Period: 1 Month

Current Location: Kolkata Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computer Science]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Hyderabad, Kolkata Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Information Technology Analyst, Software Developer, Software Development, Application Programming, Business

Process Analysis, Data Validation, Solution Architecture, Root Cause Analysis, Agile Methodology, Project

Management, Core Java, MySQL, JavaScript, Linux

Verified: Email - id Phone Number |

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

Summary

A competent professional with over 6.2 years of experience in Software Application Development (Java) Provided insightful knowledge of business process analysis (As-Is, To-Be) and design; managed application based process re-engineering as well as process customization, process optimization and provided technical solutions from stability prospective Supervised the preparation of flowcharts, block diagrams and code programs for validation and testing Identified, conceptualized and documented appropriate technical solution approaches for various business scenarios and challenges Successfully worked in projects such as:

- o Rentokil Initial Project UK biggest pesticides company
- o Wright Express Project- Largest payment service company of US
- o Crew Management System US largest airlines company
- o Smart City Project India's 3rd largest banking sector
- o GUI Development Project- UK biggest telecom service provider

Work Experience

Tata Consultancy Services as Information Technology Analyst Sep 2019 to Till Date

Project Executed: Project Name: Supply Chain Development Project (Core Application) (US Biggest Satellite Radio Company) Role: Offshore Java Team Lead Team Size: 4 Key Result Areas: Developing modules in Spring Boot, Spring Rest, Spring Data JPA, Hibernate, Java 7 and 8 versions of enhancements and change requests that receive the stories from Jira (Agile tool) Working on agile methodology, where daily onshore-offshore calls are conducted with the clients and discussed about the daily work progress of the Jira stories Analyzing production issues and executing root cause analysis of the production issues assigned Dealing with the perf environment issues and other lower environment issues and helping junior team members for any of the technical challenges and solving their issues and guiding them accordingly Providing demo to the client about POC on Spring Boot, Spring Cloud with Micro services using Netflix OSS Stack, Spring Data JPA, Spring Security, OAuth2 with Json Web Tokens as security framework Managing client call & sprint call about the daily work status done; preparing the TDR (Technical Design Requirement) documents & implementing & conducting FQA (Functionality Quality Testing) Identifying the defects & resolving the issues; enhancing software development and working on change request

Project Name: GUI Development Project (UK's largest Network Service Provider) Role: Team Lead Key Result Areas: Developed the Wholesale Telecom Billing System (GUI) using Spring Boot, Spring Data JPA

Pricewaterhouse Coopers as Senior Consultant

Nov 2018 to Aug 2019

Key Result Areas: Developed the technical design document (both HLD's and LLD's) and coding in Java Version 7 and 8 for India's 3rd largest private sector bank to develop their smart city portal using Spring Boot, Spring REST, Spring Data JPA, Spring Cloud Micro Services based on Netflix OSS Stack, Spring Security, OAuth2 with Json Web Tokens as security framework & Spring Data JPA as persistence framework Migrated the entire application of Axis Smart City Raipur Project from the legacy system of Spring MVC to Spring Cloud Micro Services based on Netflix OSS Stack Architecture

Cognizant Technology Solutions as Project Associate

Nov 2017 to Nov 2018

Key Result Areas:

Worked as a base team member in one of the largest airlines company of US as a scratch developer in travel and hospitality domain on Spring Boot/Spring Micro Services based on Netflix OSS Stack /Spring REST Framework/Hibernate/Mockito/Junit Framework/ Spring Security Used to design templates as per the industry standards best practices in Spring Boot/Spring Rest/Spring Micro Services Framework/ Spring Micro Services based on Netflix OSS Stack for the other teams to follow the template while developing the module

Infosys as Technology Analyst

Aug 2017 to Oct 2017

Worked in US Based Bank Project's Spring/Hibernate/Java development area and have developed some Restful API's as server side and also consumed some of the Restful API's for business related purposes.

Cognizant Technologies Solutions as Programmer Analyst

Feb 2014 to Jul 2017

Performing code debugging, troubleshooting of PDA Device related problems and resolving customers queries. Spearheading a project for one of US based Travel Agent Company by developing 3 modules for the project as Spring, Hibernate Developer from the scratch (BL, MVC, DAO Layers)

Working as a vertical resource in the Travel and Hospitality domain for Rentokil Project & Wright Express Edition Project (T&H Project)

Identifying issues and risks on time; formulating appropriate mitigation & contingency plans and ensuring their proper implementation

Providing support to four applications namely: PesTrak, WashTrak, Ambius and MediTrak, written in Java Language Coordinating with both internal as well as external clients in order to determine specific requirements and expectations; meeting client expectations as an indicator of quality

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computer Science) from West Bengal University of Technology (WBUT) in 2013

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
CORE JAVA	8		
Spring core and MVC	4	2018	3 Year(s) 3 Month(s)
spring boot	1.5.10	2018	3 Year(s)
Spring Rest Services	4	2018	3 Year(s)
Spring Microservices		2018	1 Year(s)
Windows XP, Windows 7 and Linux		2018	4 Year(s)
Hibernate and Mybatis	4 and 3	2018	2 Year(s)
Java Web Services (JAX-RS and JAX-WS),		2018	3 Year(s)

https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=a201029ff2e370f690edc4c510d4f5f05e540905181608440016125e540... 1/22/2021

MySQL, Oracle 9i and Oracle 12 c	2018	4 Year(s)
JavaScript	2018	0 Year(s) 2 Month(s)
Dreamweaver, Tortoise SVN	2018	2 Year(s)
Mockito Framework	2018	3 Year(s)
JUNIT	2018	3 Year(s)
gradle	2018	1 Year(s)
GitLab	2018	1 Year(s)
Lucene framework	2017	1 Year(s)

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				
Bengali				

Projects

Project Title: Crew Modernization

Client: Delta Airlines

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Nov 2017 - Till Date

Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: Working as a developer for Spring Boot, MyBatis, Spring Microservices, Spring Security, Spring Batch

Project Title: Wright Express Development Project

Client: Wright Express Corp Nature of Employment: Full Time Project Location: Kolkata

Duration: Feb 2015 - Till Date Onsite / Offsite: Offsite Team Size: 15

Role: Programmer

Skill Used: Core Java, J2EE, Spring, Hibernate and Java WebServices

Role Description: Used to work on Scratch development project using Spring and Hibernate framework

Project Details: It is a Core Application Development Project

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: General Job Type: Permanent / Temporary Physically Challenged: No Employment Status: Full time